Sheet music collection on medical themes
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Bromo-Seltzer sheet music, 5.
  - Bridal Chorus from Lohengrin (Edition DeLuxe), ca. 1910
  - The Bridge (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Bring de Banjo Ebenezer (52 popular selections), c. 1899, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - Brother's Lullaby (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Butterfly Waltz (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Butterfly Waltz (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Butterfly Waltz (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - By Normandie's Blue Hills (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - By the Sad Sea Waves (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - The Captain's Story (52 popular selections), c. 1894, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - Carnival of Venice (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Carnival of Venice (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Carnival of Venice (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Carnival of Venice (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Colonial March (52 popular selections), c. 1899, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - Columbia, My Country (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Columbia, My Country (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - Come Back to Erin (Edition DeLuxe), ca. 1910
  - Coming Thro' the Rye (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Comrades, ca. 1890-1892
  - Cradle Song (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Ciribiribin: Waltz (Edition DeLuxe), ca. 1910
  - Dance of the Hottentots (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910 (Box 13)
  - De Coontown Cakewalk (171 popular selections, version 2), c. 1900, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - De Coontown Cakewalk (52 popular selections), c. 1900, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - De Gal I Dream About (83 popular songs, version 1), c. 1898, pub. ca. 1899
  - The Dear Little Shamrock (54 popular songs), ca. 1892
  - The Dear Little Shamrock (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Difference in the Morning (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
    The words of this song advertise Bromo-Seltzer.
  - Do They Think of Me at Home? (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Do They Think of Me at Home? (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Dream Faces (74 popular songs), ca. 1898
  - Dream Faces (171 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Ehren on the Rhine (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Ehren on the Rhine (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Farewell (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - Flee as a Bird (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Flee as a Bird (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Garden of Sleep (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Garden of Sleep (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Gathered Flowers (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Gathered Flowers (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1900
  - Gathered Flowers (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Gathered Flowers (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Golden Harvester (54 popular songs), ca. 1892
  - The Golden Harvester (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Good Evening Schottische (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Good Evening Schottische (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Good Evening Schottische (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - Grandma's Shamrocks (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Grandma's Shamrocks (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Grandma's Shamrocks (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - Green Palms (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Green Palms (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Green Palms (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Green Palms (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - "Guard the Flag" March (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - "Guard the Flag" March (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Hail Columbia (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Hail Columbia (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Heart Bowed Down (54 popular songs), ca.1893
  - The Heart Bowed Down (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - The Heart Bowed Down (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Hi-Tiddley-Hi-Ti (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Home Again (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Home Again (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Home, Sweet Home (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Home, Sweet Home (54 popular songs), ca. 1890-1893
  - Home, Sweet Home (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Home, Sweet Home (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - The Hornpipe Polka (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - How Can I Leave Thee (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - I Cannot Say Good-bye (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - I Dreamt I Dwelt in Marble Halls (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - I Dreamt I Dwelt in Marble Halls (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - I Love My Love (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - I Whistle and Wait for Katie (54 popular songs), early 1890s
  - I Whistle and Wait for Katie (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - In Glory He Ascendeth (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - In Glory He Ascendeth (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - In Glory He Ascendeth (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - In the Gloaming (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - In the Gloaming (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Intermezzo from Cavalleria Rusticana (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Intermezzo from Cavalleria Rusticana (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Intermezzo from Cavalleria Rusticana (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - I've Worked Eight Hours This Day (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Jolly Brother's Galop (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899 (Box 14)
  - Juanita (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Just A Little Sunshine Waltz (83 popular songs, version 1), c. 1892, pub. ca. 1899
  - Just A Little Sunshine Waltz (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Just A Little Sunshine Waltz (171 popular selections version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Just A Little Sunshine Waltz (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Just A Little Sunshine Waltz (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Kathleen Mavourneen (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Kathleen Mavourneen (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Katie Callahan (83 popular songs, version 1), c. 1895, pub. ca. 1899
  - Keep for Me a Trusting Heart (83 popular songs, version 1), c. 1897, pub. ca. 1899
  - Keep for Me a Trusting Heart (83 popular songs, version 2), c. 1897, pub ca. 1899
  - Keep for Me a Trusting Heart (171 popular selections, version 1), c. 1897, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - Keep for Me a Trusting Heart (171 popular selections, version 2), c. 1897, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - Larboard Watch (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Last Night (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Last Night (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Last Night 171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Lead, Kindly Light (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Let Me Dream Again (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Let Me Dream Again (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Lights Far Out At Sea (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - List to Me (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Listen to the Mockingbird (83 popular songs, version 1), c. 1897, pub. ca. 1899
  - Listen to the Mockingbird (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Lost Chord (54 popular songs), early 1890s
  - The Lost Chord (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Lost Chord (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Love, I Will Love You Ever (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Love, I Will Love You Ever (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Love's But A Dream (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Love's But A Dream (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Love's But A Dream (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Love's Golden Dream (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Love's Golden Dream (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Love's Golden Dream (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Love's Old Sweet Song (54 popular songs), ca. 1890-1892
  - Love's Old Sweet Song (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Lullaby from "Erminie", 1890-1892
  - Lullaby from "Erminie" (54 popular songs), early 1890s
  - Lullaby from "Erminie" (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Lullaby from "Erminie" (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Lullaby from "Erminie" (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Maid of the Mill (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Marching Through Georgia (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Manila Quickstep (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Manila Quickstep (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Mary and John: Lover's Quarrel, 1890s
    Not part of a named collection.
  - Mary of Argyle (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Maryland! My Maryland! (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Maryland! My Maryland! (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Miller and the Maid (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - The Miller and the Maid (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Morning Prayer (Edition DeLuxe), ca. 1910
  - Murphy's Head or, After Kelly's Party, c. 1892, pub. ca. 1892
    This individual song, copyright by Emerson Drug Co., directly advertises Bromo-Seltzer as a remedy for a hangover. See also the song, "The Difference in the Morning."
  - My Best Girl's March (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - My Old Kentucky Home (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - My Old Kentucky Home (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - My Old Kentucky Home (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - My Sweetheart at the Door (74 popular songs), c. 1894, pub. ca. 1895
  - My Sweetheart at the Door (74 popular songs), c. 1894, pub. ca. 1898
    Includes list of "New selections, added January 1st 1898."
  - My Sweetheart at the Door (83 popular songs, version 1), c. 1894, pub. ca. 1899
  - My Sweetheart, Kitty Hayes (52 popular selections), c. 1894, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - Nearer, My God, To Thee (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910 (Box 15)
  - Nearer, My God, To Thee (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Nearer, My God, To Thee (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - Never to Part (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Non É Ver 'Tis Not True, ca. 1890-1892
  - Non É Ver 'Tis Not True (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Non É Ver 'Tis Not True (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Norah, My Village Queen (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - O Fair Dove, Fond Dove (Edition DeLuxe), ca. 1910
  - The Old Arm Chair, ca. 1890-1892
  - The Old Arm Chair (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Old Barn Polka (74 popular songs), c. 1895, pub. ca. 1895
  - Old Barn Polka (84 popular songs, version 1), c. 1895, pub. ca. 1899
  - Old Black Joe (Edition DeLuxe), ca. 1910
  - Old Familiar Faces (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Old Farm House on the Hill (Editions DeLuxe), ca. 1910
  - Old Folks at Home (74 popular songs), ca. 1898
    Includes "New Selections, Added January 1st 1898."
  - Old Folks at Home (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - The Old Oaken Bucket (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - The Old Oaken Bucket (171 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Old Sexton (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - The Old Ship (83 popular songs, version 1), c. 1891, pub. ca. 1899
  - Old Year Dies To-Night (52 popular selections), c. 1885, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - Only One in the World for Me (171 popular selections, version 1), c. 1895, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - Only One in the World for Me (52 popular selections), c. 1895, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - Only To-Night or, The Last Waltz (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Our Jack's Come Home To-day (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Over the Moonlit Sea (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Over the Moonlit Sea (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - Pilgrim's Chorus from Tannhauser (Editions DeLuxe), ca. 1910
  - Playmates (54 popular songs), ca. 1890-1892
  - Playmates (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Prince Imperial: Galop (Edition DeLuxe), ca. 1910
  - Queen of My Heart (54 popular songs), ca. 1890-1892
  - Red, White and Blue (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Red, White and Blue (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Robin Adair (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Rock of Ages, ca. 1891
    Unlike the other individual songs, this one has testimonials dated from 1889 to 1891.
  - Rocked in the Cradle of the Deep (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Rocked in the Cradle of the Deep (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Rocked in the Cradle of the Deep (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Rocked in the Cradle of the Deep (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Rose-Bud Waltz (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Rosita Waltz (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Rosita Waltz (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Sailing; or, Ere Jack Comes Home Again (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Sailing; or, Ere Jack Comes Home Again (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Sailing; or, Ere Jack Comes Home Again (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Sailing; or, Ere Jack Comes Home Again (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - The School-Bell March (74 popular songs), c. 1894, pub. ca. 1895
  - The School-Bell March (83 popular songs, version 1), c. 1894, pub. ca. 1899
  - The School-Bell March (171 popular selections, version 2), c. 1894, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - Schubert's Serenade (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Schubert's Serenade (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Schubert's Serenade (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Schubert's Serenade (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Silver Brook (74 popular songs), c. 1895, pub. ca. 1895
  - Silver Brook (83 popular songs, version 2), c. 1895, pub. ca. 1899
  - Since Molly Moved Away (83 popular songs, version 1), c. 1896. pub. ca. 1899
  - Sing, Sweet Bird (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Sing, Sweet Bird (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Sing, Sweet Bird (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Song For Me (83 popular songs), ca. 1899
  - The Star-Spangled Banner (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - The Star-Spangled Banner (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Starlight Polka (83 popular songs,version 1), ca. 1899
  - Starlight Polka (83 popular songs,version 2), ca. 1899
  - Starlight Polka (171 popular selections,version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Starlight Polka (171 popular selections,version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Stay Home To-night with the Old Folks (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Stay Home To-night with the Old Folks (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - Strangers Yet (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Sweet Chimes of Long Ago (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Sweet Chimes of Long Ago (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - The Sweetest Girl of All (83 popular songs, version 1), c. 1895, pub. ca. 1899
  - The Sweetest Girl of All (171 popular selections, version 1), c. 1895, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - The Sweetest Girl of All (171 popular selections, version 2), c. 1895, pub. ca. 1900-1910
  - Sweetheart's Waltz (83 popular songs, version 1), c. 1894, pub. ca. 1899
  - Sweethearts and Wives (54 popular songs), ca. 1893
    While most sheet music in the collection "54 Popular Songs" shows a woman playing a Chickering piano, this piece advertizes the Stieff piano. "See the Stieff Piano at the World's Exposition, Chicago, 1893."
  - Sweethearts and Wives (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Sweethearts and Wives (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Sweethearts and Wives (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Ta Ra! Ra! Boom De Ay!, ca. 1892 (Box 16)
    Testimonials for Bromo Seltzer dated 1892 on last page.
  - Take Back the Heart (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Take Back the Heart (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Tea-Bud Schottische (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Tea-Bud Schottische (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - Then You Wink The Other Eye, ca. 1890-1892
  - Then You Wink The Other Eye (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Then You'll Remember Me (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Then You'll Remember Me (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Then You'll Remember Me (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - Then You'll Remember Me (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Thine Eyes So Blue and Tender (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - Thine Eyes So Blue and Tender (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Thine Eyes So Blue and Tender (171 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - 'Tis the Last Rose of Summer (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - 'Tis the Last Rose of Summer (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Tommy Reilly (74 popular songs), c. 1891, pub. ca. 1895
  - Under the Double Eagle: March - Two Step (Edition DeLuxe), ca. 1910
    Two copies.
  - The University Polka (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Until Then (171 popular selections, version 1, ca. 1900-1910
  - Until Then (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - Venetian Boat Song (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - A Warrior Bold (74 popular songs), ca. 1895
  - A Warrior Bold (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - Were We Lovers Then? (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - What Are the Wild Waves Saying? (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - What Are the Wild Waves Saying? (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - What Are the Wild Waves Saying? (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - When Life is Brightest (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - When Life is Brightest (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - When the Angels Have Lifted the Veil (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - When the Angels Have Lifted the Veil (52 popular selections), ca. 1900-1910
  - When the Swallows Homeward Fly (83 popular songs, version 1), ca. 1899
  - When the Swallows Homeward Fly (83 popular songs, version 2), ca. 1899
  - When the Swallows Homeward Fly (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - When the Swallows Homeward Fly (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - When You and I Were Young, Maggie (Edition DeLuxe), ca. 1910
  - Will You Dance With Me, Sally? (171 popular selections, version 1), ca. 1900-1910
  - Will You Dance With Me, Sally? (171 popular selections, version 2), ca. 1900-1910
  - Yellow Jacket Polka (52 popular selections), c. 1894, pub. ca. 1900-1910
- Miscellaneous, 6.
  - St. Jacobs Oil sheet music
    St. Jacobs Oil was manufactured as far back as 1870 by the Charles A. Vogeler Company, Baltimore, Maryland, as a remedy for pain. The company published the "St Jacobs Oil Series of Music" similar to the Bromo-Seltzer sheet music. There is considerable overlap among titles. The sheet music also contains advertisements for Diamond Vera-Cura, a remedy for dyspepsia. As in the case of Bromo-Seltzer the music could be obtained in drug stores or by writing to the company, and enclosing a stamp and a product wrapper. The most recent pieces of sheet music (ca. 1905) were published by St. Jacobs Oil, Ltd, Baltimore.
    - Brother's Lullaby, ca. 1890
    - Courting in the Moonlight, ca. 1905
    - The Dear Little Shamrock, ca. 1890
    - Flee as a Bird, ca. 1890
    - The Heart Bowed Down, ca. 1890
    - Hearts and Homes (65 popular selections), 1890s
    - Home, Sweet Home, ca. 1890
    - In the Gloaming, ca, 1890
    - Jessie, the Flow'r o' Dumblane (65 popular selections), 1890s
    - Larboard Watch (25 popular selections), 1880s
    - Last Night, ca. 1905
    - Let Me Dream Again (25 popular selections), 1880s
    - The Marseilles Hymn, ca. 1890
    - Non É Ver ('Tis Not True) (25 popular songs), 1880s
    - O Fair Dove, O Fond Dove, ca. 1890
    - O Rest in the Lord, ca. 1890
    - The Old Arm Chair, ca. 1890
    - The Old Sexton (65 popular selections), 1890s
    - Take Back the Heart, ca. 1890
    - Then You'll Remember Me, ca. 1890
    - Three Fishers Went Sailing, ca. 1890
    - A Warrior Bold, ca. 1890
    - When the Swallows Homeward Fly (25 popular selections), 1880s
    - Wild Flowers, n.d.
      This piece is part of the "International Series, Copyright and Standard Vocal and Instrumental Music" published by St. Jacobs Oil, Ltd., Baltimore.
  - Beecham's Music Portfolio advertizing Beecham's Pills (Box 17)
    Beecham's pills were advertized to women for "bilious and nervous disorders" and a variety of other ailments.
    - Beecham's Portfolio volumes (Box 17)
      These small format (20 cm.) booklets of popular music were published by Thomas Beecham, Proprietor of Beecham's Pills, St. Helens, Lancashire. The collection includes volumes 1-3, 5 -6, 11-18, 20. There is also a revised volume 2. Each volume contained 30 pieces numbered from 1 to 600. They could be purchased from the company.
    - Beecham's individual songs
      The collection also contains individual songs from the 20 volumes in the same small format. They were given away by drug stores and date from the turn of the 20th century. The collection contains numbers 2-6, 9-10, 12, 14, 20, 22, 24, 26, 55, 111, 121, 123, 147, 244, 248, 251, 254, 255, 257, 263, 272, 279, 282, 287, 289, 292, 299, 302, 311, 313, 332, 335, 337, 341, 343, 351, 387, 392, 541.
  - Musical shows on medical themes
    - Doctor, Doctor!: A Musical Comedy in One Act, 1973 (Box 18)
      Lyrics by John Jakes and Gilbert M. Martin, music by Gilbert M. Martin, book by John Jakes. Music and lyrics copyright by McAfee Music Corporation, New York, 1973. Book copyright by John Jakes, 1973. Based on Le Médecin malgré lui (The Physician in Spite of Himself) by Moliére.
    - Oh, Doctor!: A Musical Comedy in Three Acts, 1919
      Book by Gene Markey, lyrics by Tom Groves, music by Werner Janssen. Hanover, N.H.: The College Bookstore, Dartmouth College, 1919. Performed by the Dartmouth Dramatic Association. Two acts take place in the office of Dr. Brown in New York. Book contains the songs but not the dialogue of the play.
    - Oh Doctor!: An Operetta in Two Acts, 1931
      Book and lyrics by Estelle Merrymon Clark, music by Palmer John Clark. Chicago: The Raymond A. Hoffman Company, c. 1931. Set in a sanitarium and spring near the Mexican Border owned and operated by Dr. Drinkwater.
    - Santa Has the Grippe: A Humorous Christmas Cantata, 1907
      Words by Harriet D. Castle Carmichael, music by Ira B. Wilson. Dayton, Ohio: The Lorenz Publishing Co., c. 1907.
  - Other medical music
    - Nine Medical Songs
      Words by J. Blumfield, G. H. Ransome, and F. H., music by C. N. Chadborn. London: St. George's Hospital, 1890s. These are songs by physicians or medical students for their peers. Titles are "Oh, Would I Were a Surgeon," A Song of St. George's," "Back to the Corner Again," "The Veteran Stethoscope," "The Love-Sick Bacillus," "A Lay of the Dissecting Room," "The Lament of the Large White Kidney," "A Bronchitic's Love Song," and "To a Hospital Nurse."
    - Medical Students Songbook